Clarisse Duryee

1991 - American / French Interaction Designer 07 69 29 42 86 duryeeclarisse@gmail.com Portfolio website



Clarisse is an outgoing American/French woman with a good sense of humor. In her spare time she enjoys working on game projects, playing video an board games. She is a passionate individual that strives to always do achieve her goals.

One of Clarisse's core strengths is being able to take a team of different talents and come up with creative solutions to make the most of everyone's different approaches. She works equally as well in a team as well as independently and brings a great set of knowledge, experience, and ideas wherever she goes. She is excellent at multitasking several different aspects within a project whether it be the creative aspects to the organization and business aspects and always meets her deadlines.

Clarisse has been building her own degree to suit her ambitions within the Game Development field, currently she is completing a bachelors in the Interaction Design program at Malmö University and has several other creative as well as business courses under her belt.

During courses as well as privately she has done several design, art and gaming projects. These projects and more can be viewed on her portfolio website

Personal Characteristics

Social Hardworking

Honest Dependable

Team player Solid Leader

Problem solver Creative

Organized Flexible

Technical Knowledge

Windows Office 365 suite

Graphic Design Programs:

Photoshop Indesign Illustrator

Sound Design programs:

Audacity Premier Pro

Programming:

CSS, HTML, Javascript, C#

Engineering:

Arduino prototyping

Previous Experience

2021-2022

Temporary Game tester – Massive Entertainement

Massive Entertainement hired temporary testers for testing a game over a month period as well as three other occassions where she was called on to test several game projects.

She was able to give good feedback that to the team as well as reflections that on the product that was apperciated by the team. After her initial round she was invited back to test other products aside from the one she started out with.

GAME TESTING, GAMING, FEEDBACK

2016 - 2021

Independant Game Testing:

Subnautica & Subnautica: Below Zero – Unknown Worlds Entertainment

Clarisse partook in the alpha testing of Subnautica 1 & 2 In both the closed alpha and later in the public betas. She took part in game testing and provided feedback and bug reports back to the developers.

GAME TESTING, GAMING, ERROR LOGGING, FEEDBACK

2019

Project: The Pick-your-own-adventure text-based RPG

Clarisse led a game project with a team of 6, three writers, three programmers. The game was produced in Twine, a program dedicated to creating text-based games. Clarisse wrote, coded, as well as led the team with deadlines and stand-up meetings. The game is set in 1888 London, Jack the Ripper's story. The protagonist must obtain clues and create a profile of Jack with usage of the pseudoscience Alienism. The player obtains clues and builds their own custom Ripper from these interpretations and had 12 different endings.

PROJECT LEAD, WRITING, PROGRAMMING

2019

Project: Audiosit

An interactive art performance consisted of a team of 5. Audiosit was written, directed partially voice and edited by Clarisse. The audiosit was a horror/thriller genre performed on the listener blindfolded and the team performed actions upon their person after they were made to sign a concent agreement. The project was overviewed by award winning sound designer Martin Hennel who found the peice to be both masterful and innovative.

PROJECT LEADING, WRITING, DIRECTING, EDITING, VOICE ACTING, SOUND MIXING

2017

Personal Project: RPG Board Game

The Inquisition Board Game

A Co-Op board game meant to be played with two groups separately, a team of humans vs a team of vampires. Both teams can compromise the other and is based on 5th Edition Dungeons and Dragons. The players are unaware that the other team exists for the majority of the game. Clarisse developed an application that could create a customized game so it can be picked up at any time by anyone.

WRITING, GAME DESIGNING, APPLICATION DESIGN, GRAPHIC DESIGN

2014

Population Census - Habas City Hall - France

Clarisse led and organized the population census in 2014 successfully. A successful count is when the government appointed worker finds no errors within the four types of paperwork as well as the data entries being correct, something which in the past (prior to Clarisse) had been elusive. Clarisse then organized all the paperwork as well as created a procedure to facilitate rapid entry of data in the Government program. This procedure included a database She developed a guide to ensure that future census leaders could follow her innovative example and always have successful census counts.

ORGANIZATION, DATABASE, PAPERWORK, LEADING

Education

2020 - present

Interaction Design - Malmö University - Sweden

Currently Clarisse is enrolled in her final year of Interaction Design. This field of study has offered many opportunities to continue her team development skills as a leader and a team member.

When given the freedom of topic choice, Clarisse has always focused on game development and exploration.

Clarisse has led and create several functioning protypes both on her own and within group work. Clarisse is a natural leader and is able to work with diverse ranges of skillsets from her team members to put forward their collective vision.

Prototyping with the power of the Arduino and programming skills have allowed for her to bring projects to life. Projects such as a detuned plant so the user knows when to water it, a smart bird house that allows users to get to know the birds in their area to the wild idea of a game involving automated smell dispersion and storytelling,

CONCEPTUALIZATION, PROTOTYPING, PROGRAMMING, RESEARCH, USER TESTING, CO-DESIGNING, UI UX DESIGNING

2017-2019 Independant program

Clarisse built her own 180 credit degree composed of buisness, administration & the creative arts across Swedish universities.

Digital Service Management & Innovation – Lund University - Sweden

Clarisse obtained knowledge on digital service and how customers/users utilize certain functions such as applications, websites and web services.

Leadership & Organisation from a Global Perspective – Malmö University - Sweden

Clarisse took this course to learn more about Leadership and management from a Globalist perspective due to the melting pot that is the EU she felt it necessary to understand and learn about all potential work environments.

Buisness Writing in English – Linnaeus University – Sweden

Due to having studied buisness in France Clarisse felt it nessesary to update her skills for a globalist economy and took this course in order to obtain correct formulae that belonged to the english buisness communication field.

Storytelling & Narration across media – Malmö University - Sweden

This course involved two large group projects which Clarisse led successfully. Storytelling through audio with the creation of an Audiosit and a Pick-your-own-adventure text based RPG using open source program: Twine.

Character Design - Malmö University - Sweden

On her free time Clarisse loves to write and create games, review games and overall a storytelling enthusist. She took this course to obtain theoretical and practial knowledge on character creation and developement.

Digital Image Editing – Linnaeus University – Sweden

Clarisse on her own has been using Photoshop since 2009 and felt it nessesary to obtain certification to confirm her Adobe Photoshop tool skills.

Illustration - Linnaeus University - Sweden

Study & Application of Illustration techniques and design

Clarisse is a skilled artist and through this course obtained knowledge on how to utilize and focus creativity for a business-driven purpose.

Digital Tools for Design Process – Linnaeus University – Sweden

Clarisse wanted to learn more Adobe tools and during this course she learned to use and master InDesign and Illustrator.

2012-2015 Professional Baccalaureate with honors—Lycée Borda - France

Clarisse earned a degree with honors within the work environment as this degree is only achieved with work experience. To earn this degree, she obtained a paid internship in Habas City Hall where at the end of her degree she was offered a job as secretary manager.